fashionmodeldirectory.com 2019-03-20

# Privacy Policy | The FMD

## 1\. Overview

This Privacy Policy applies to the Fashion Model Directory and its operated websites and subdomains (“Sites”). The Fashion Model Directory (“we”, "FMD" or “us”) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared. This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by the Fashion Model Directory when you access Fashionmodeldirectory.com and all subordinated domains and projects, how the information will be used, the steps we take to protect such information and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. By visiting the Site, you accept the privacy practices described in this Policy. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.   
This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. Capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meaning given them in our Terms. The use of information collected through our Sites shall be limited to the purposes under this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. 

Except as otherwise noted in this Privacy Policy, Fashion Model Directory is a data controller (as that term is used under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)), which means that we decide how and why the information you provide to us is processed. Contact details are provided in Section 14 below. This Policy may be amended or updated from time to time to reflect changes in our practices with respect to the Processing of your information, or changes in applicable law. We encourage you to read this Policy carefully, and to regularly check this page to review any changes we might make. 

Definitions:  
**“Personal Data”** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.  
**“Public Area”** means the area of the Site that can be accessed both by Users and Visitors, without needing to log in.  
**“Restricted Area”** means the area of the Site that can be accessed only by Users, and where access requires logging in.  
**“User”** means an employee, agent, or representative of a Client, who primarily uses the restricted areas of the Site for the purpose of accessing the Service in such capacity.  
**“Visitor”** means an individual other than a User, who uses the public area, but has no access to the restricted areas of the Site or Service.

## 2.What Information We May Collect & Process

We collect different types of information from your use of our Website with your specific knowledge and consent. The processing is necessary for providing the Service in accordance with our Terms of Service and the processing of which is carried out in our legitimate interests, which are further explained in the section “How We Use the Information We Collect” of this Policy. We may also process data upon your consent, asking for it as appropriate.

**“Personal Information”** means information that is about any individual, or from which any individual is directly or indirectly identifiable.

**“Process”, “Processing” or “Processed”** means anything that is done with any Personal Information, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.

Under certain circumstances and depending on applicable law, some of this Other Information may constitute Personal Information. Personal Information together with Other Information is hereinafter referred to as **“User Information”.**

We may Process the following categories;

 _Personal details:_ username or log in details; password; your name (in rare cases); area of interest (in rare cases)  
_Demographic information:_ age group (to confirm);   
_Contact details:_ email address; telephone (in rare cases)  
_Location information:_ location data that describes the geographic location of your device (“Location Data”).  
_Views and opinions:_ any views and opinions that you or other users choose to send to us, or publicly post about us on social media platforms or in the Website.  

## 3\. What Information We Do Not Collect & Process

We do not collect or otherwise Process Personal Information about race or ethnicity, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life, any actual or alleged criminal offences or penalties, or any other information that may be deemed to be sensitive under GDPR (collectively, “Sensitive Personal Information”) in the ordinary course of our business.

Where it becomes necessary to Process Sensitive Personal Information under GDPR, we would rely on one of the following legal bases:

_Compliance with applicable law:_ We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is required or permitted by applicable law;

_Detection and prevention of crime:_ We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is necessary for the detection or prevention of crime (including the prevention of fraud);

_Establishment, exercise or defense of legal rights:_ We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where the Processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal rights; or

_Consent:_ We may Process your Sensitive Personal Information where we have, in accordance with applicable law, obtained your prior, express consent prior to Processing your Sensitive Personal Information.

_Children:_ The Services are not intended for use by children, especially those under 18. No one under the age of 13 should provide any Personal Information. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 18 without obtaining parental consent. If you are under 18 years of age, then please do not use or access the Service at any time or in any manner. If we learn that Personal Data has been collected on the Service from persons under 18 years of age and without verifiable parental consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under 18 years of age has obtained an Account on the Service, then you may alert us at privacy@fashionmodeldirectory.com and request that we delete that child’s Personal Data from our systems. 

## 4\. How We Collect Information

We may collect User Information about you from the following sources: 

**_4.1 User-provided Information_** \- We may obtain your Personal Information when you provide it to us across our Services (e.g. register for site membership or create a profile or account on any part of the Services; perform search queries through the Website; contact us via email, telephone or by any other means. We may also collect or obtain your Personal Information that you clearly choose to make public, including via social media (e.g., we may collect information from your social media profile(s) if you make a public post about us. 

**_4.2 Automatically Collected Information_** \- When a User or Visitor uses the Service, we may automatically record certain information from the User’s or Visitor’s device by using various types of technology including cookies, web beacons. This “automatically collected" information may include Non-precise information about the approximate physical location (“Geo IP Data”), Internet Protocol (“IP”) address or other device address or ID, internet service provider (“ISP”), web browser and/or device type, Advertising ID, eTags, JavaScript, pixel tags, device ID tracking, anonymous identifiers, cookies, Log files, local Shared Objects, such as Flash cookies, and Local Storage, such as HTML5. 

**_4.3 Content and Advertising information_** \- If you choose to interact with any third-party content or advertising on our website, we may receive User Information about you from the relevant third party. 

**_4.4 Third party information_** \- We may collect or obtain your Personal Information from third parties who provide it to us. This may include third-party affiliate network operators; referral sources; social network sites or services (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.). If you use a third-party connection or log-in (e.g., Facebook Connect, Twitter, or Google+) to access the Website, create a profile on any part of the Services, access our content or forward our content to another person, platform or service, we may also receive your username or email address for those third- party services or other information available about you or collected from you on those services.

This may include but is not limited to: information collected using such methods and technologies about (i) your visits to, and interaction and engagement with, the website, content and ads on third party websites, applications, platforms and other media channels (“Channels”), and (ii) your interaction with emails including the content and ads therein (collectively, “Online Data”).

We also may use these technologies to collect information regarding a Visitor or User’s interaction with email messages, such as whether the Visitor or User opens, clicks on, or forwards a message. This information is gathered from all Users and Visitors.

## 5\. How We May Use Your Information

The purposes for which we may Process User Information, subject to applicable law, include:

**_5.1 Operations_** \- We use the information to operate, maintain, enhance and provide all features of the Service, to provide the services and information that you request, to respond to comments and questions and to provide support to users of the Service. We process the same solely in accordance with the directions provided by the applicable Client or User.

**_5.2 Improvements_** \- We use the information to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our Visitors and Users, to improve the Service, to develop new features, and functionality, providing personalized content to you and notifying you of changes to any of our Services.

**_5.2 Communications_** \- Communicating with you via any means (including via email, telephone, text message, social media, post or in person) regarding news items and other information in which you may be interested, subject to ensuring that such communications are provided to you in compliance with applicable law; maintaining and updating your contact information where appropriate; and obtaining your prior, opt-in consent where required. We may provide direct marketing to you as set out in Section 6 below. 

## 6\. Cookies, Similar Technologies and Online Behavioral Advertising

_Cookies-_ The FMD may use cookies and other tracking technologies to analyze trends, administer Services, track users’ movements around the Website and on third party sites, devices and applications, and to gather demographic information about our user base. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on the Website. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). Please see our **Cookie Policy** for more information, including a more in-depth explanation of what cookies are, the different types of cookies used on the Website, and how to change or delete them. 

_Tracking Technologies & Analytics-_

Tracking technologies on the Services may be deployed by FMD and/or by our service providers, advertisers or partners. Certain tracking technologies enable us to assign a unique identifier to you, and relate information about your use of the Services to other information about you, including your User Information. We may match information collected from you through different means or at different times and use such information along with offline and online information obtained from other sources (including from third parties), including, but not limited to, demographic information and updated contact information, for the purposes of learning more about you so we can provide you with relevant content and advertising.

We use Google Analytics to measure and evaluate access to and traffic on the Site, and create user navigation reports for our Site administrators. Google operates independently from us and has its own privacy policy, which we strongly suggest you review. Google may use the information collected through Google Analytics to evaluate Users' and Visitors’ activity on our Site. For more information, see [Google Analytics Privacy and Data Sharing](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

We take measures to protect the technical information collected by our use of Google Analytics. The data collected will only be used on a need to know basis to resolve technical issues, administer the Site and identify visitor preferences; but in this case, the data will be in non-identifiable form. We do not use any of this information to identify Visitors or Users.

When you receive email messages from us, we may use web beacons, customized links, clear GIFs or similar technologies to determine whether the email has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you with more focused email communications or other information, and/or to aggregate that information with other data we collect to use for some or all of the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

We and our partners (including but not limited to advertising partners, affiliates, and analytics providers) also may use technologies such as pixel tags, e-tags, IP addresses, Local Shared Objects, Local Storage, Flash cookies and HTML5 to analyze trends; administer the Services; collect and store information such as user settings, anonymous browser identifiers and video viewing history; supplement our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement; track users’ location and movements around the Services; gather demographic information about our user base; and to improve our understanding of traffic on the Services, visitor behavior, and responses to promotional campaigns. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these third-party companies on an individual and aggregated basis. For example, we may connect information about your IP address to known corporate or User Information and use the associated information related to aggregate content preferences to assist in our efforts to market services to you or the originating corporation(s). Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing Local Storage. To manage Flash Local Shared Objects please click [here](http://www.adobe.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

_Interest Based Advertising -_

The FMD and/or certain third parties may collect information about you for online behavioral advertising (“OBA”) purposes in order for you to receive relevant interest-based advertising on the website. OBA is also referred to as interest-based advertising. It is the collection of data from different sources and across different platforms in order to predict an individual’s preferences or interest and to deliver to that individual, or his/her computer, smart phone or tablet, advertising based on his/her assumed preference or interest inferred from the collection of data pertaining to that individual or others who may have a similar profile or similar interests. 

In collaboration with these third parties, we collect information about our visitors and users over time and across different platforms when they use these platforms or interact with them. Individuals may submit information directly on our Sites or on platforms run by third parties, or by interacting with us, our advertisements, or emails they receive from us or from third parties. We may use special tools that are commonly used for this purpose, such as cookies, beacons, pixels, tags, mobile advertising IDs, flash cookies, and similar technologies. We may have access to databases of information collected by our business partners. 

We, or the third parties with which we work, use the information collected as described above to understand the various activities and to send you OBA. For example, if you read an article about a particular subject on our site, we may use cookies from a vendor to later serve you an advertisement for a particular product or service related to the viewed article. If we know what ads you are shown, we can try not to show you the same ones repeatedly. These third-party vendors may connect information about pages you visit on the Services with information about pages you visit on other Channels and show you advertising based on this combined information. These advertisements may appear when you are visiting a different section of the website. Likewise, third party vendors may serve you advertisements when you visit the website based on your interaction. 

Visitors may opt out of receiving interest-based advertising by advertising networks that may be delivered to them on our platform and other websites. For information about how to opt out of tracking methods for these entities and others, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). These features will opt a Visitor out of many – but not all - of the interest-based advertising activities in which we or third parties engage. More information can be obtained by visiting the following websites <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>; and <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.For more details about OBA and opting out, see Section 14 below. 

Online Data is aggregated with the Other Information and data we collect as described in this Privacy Policy and/or similar data collected by partners to create groups of users and certain general-interest categories or segments that we have inferred based on (a) demographic or interest data and GeoIP Data, (b) the pages you view and links you click when viewing an email or using the Services and those of our partners, and/or (c) the search terms you enter when using certain search services. We use this information to get a more accurate picture of audience interests in order to serve ads we believe are more relevant to your interests. We store page views, clicks and search terms used for ad personalization targeting separately from your Personal Information. 

## 7\. What Information We Disclose to Third Parties

We may disclose your User Information to other entities within the Company group, for legitimate business purposes (including operating the Website, and providing services to you), in accordance with applicable law. In addition, we may disclose your User Information to: 

**_7.1 Third Parties_** \- We work with third party service providers who provide website, hosting, maintenance, and other services for us. These third parties may have access to, or process Personal Data or Client Data as part of providing those services for us. We limit the information provided to these service providers to that which is reasonably necessary for them to perform their functions, and our contracts with them require them to maintain the confidentiality of such information. We may disclose information to:   
(i) any relevant third-party acquirer(s), in the event that we sell or transfer all or any relevant portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation);   
(ii) any relevant third-party provider, where our website use third party plugins or content. If you choose to interact with any such advertising, plugins or content, information about your activities on the website to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests may be shared with the relevant third-party provider. If you click or tap on or otherwise interact with an advertisement, the advertiser may assume that you meet its target criteria;   
(iii) to third parties whose practices are not covered by this Privacy Policy (e.g., third party providers of goods and services, marketing and advertising companies and agencies, content publishers and retailers).   
(iv) Some of our advertisers may use third party advertising service companies to serve advertisements, and perform related services when you interact with the Website. Often, these third-party advertising companies employ cookies and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of website, app and email advertisements and to create a record of interaction with our content that they use in conjunction with their advertising which appears on other sites or applications, or for reporting website traffic, app use, statistics, advertisement data and/or other activities on the Website. We also engage third party providers to assist with the segmentation of this data.   
(v) We may also engage third parties for the purpose of recognizing our users and delivering interest-based content and advertisements to them. We may share your User Information with our partners such as your name, postal address, email, or other identifier. Our partners may also: (i) collect information directly from your device, such as your IP address, device ID, advertising ID, and information about your browser or operating system; (ii) combine User Information about you received from FMD with information about you from other sites or services; and (iii) place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. 

**_7.2 Law Enforcement, Legal Process and Compliance_** \- We may disclose Personal Data or other information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws, in response to a facially valid court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant, or to otherwise cooperate with law enforcement or other governmental agencies. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Data or other information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to (i) take precautions against liability, (ii) protect ourselves or others from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses or activity, (iii) investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, (iv) protect the security or integrity of the Service and any facilities or equipment used to make the Service available, or (v) protect our property or other legal rights, enforce our contracts, or protect the rights, property, or safety of others. 

**_7.3 Non Personally Identifiable Information_** \- We may make certain automatically-collected, aggregated, or otherwise non-personally-identifiable information available to third parties for various purposes, including (i) compliance with various reporting obligations; (ii) for business or marketing purposes; or (iii) to assist such parties in understanding our Users’ and Visitors’ interests, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, and/or functionality available through the Service. 

## 8\. Transfers of Information 

Because of the international nature of our business, we may need to transfer your User Information to third parties as noted in Section 9 above, in connection with the purposes set out in this Policy. For this reason, we may transfer your User Information to other countries that may have different laws and data protection compliance requirements to those that apply in the country in which you are located. The FMD is committed to subjecting all Personal Information received from European Union (E.U.) member countries and Switzerland. Information collected through our website may be stored and processed in the United States, Europe, or any other country. We may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the European Union or European Economic Area, please note that we will not transfer information, including personal data, to a country outside of the European Union or European Economic Area. 

We will comply with GDPR requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information from Europe to the U.S. Also, we may transfer your data to the U.S., the EEA, or other countries or regions deemed by the European Commission to provide adequate protection of personal data in connection with storage and processing of data, fulfilling your requests, and operating the Service. 

## 9\. Data Security 

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect your User Information against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure, unauthorized access, and other unlawful or unauthorized forms of Processing, in accordance with applicable law. In certain instances we may use Secure Sockets Layer encryption and/or transfer certain User Information in a non-human readable format to provide protection. However, we cannot guarantee there will not be a breach, and we are not responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of any third parties. Because the internet is an open system, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will implement reasonable measures to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to us using the internet. Any such transmission is at your own risk and you are responsible for ensuring that any Personal Information that you send to us are sent securely. 

## 10\. Data Retention 

We take every reasonable step to ensure that your User Information is only Processed for the minimum period necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. The criteria for determining the duration for which we will keep your User Information are as follows: we will retain copies of your User Information in a form that permits identification only for as long as is necessary in connection with the purposes set out in this Policy, unless applicable law requires a longer retention period. Unless there is a specific legal requirement for us to keep the information, we plan to retain it for no longer than is necessary to fulfill a legitimate business need. Except as may be set forth in this Privacy Policy, Online Data is retained by FMD for not more than 180 days after which it shall expire. However, the 180-day period may commence again if the same user subsequently visits or interacts with an ad, email, the Website. 

## 11\. Your Choices: What Can you Do to Control your Information? 

You may directly take steps to change your preferences as follows:

_Location Based Services_ \- You may opt-out of having your Precise Location Data collected by The FMD at any time by editing the appropriate setting on your mobile device (which is usually located in the Settings area of your device). 

_Cookies and Pixel Tags_ \- You may stop or restrict cookies and pixel tags on your computer or purge cookies from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. However, if you “turn off,” purge, or disable cookies or pixel tags, although you may still use the Website, you may not be able to use all of the features, functions, or services available on the Website. For more information on the types of cookies we use please see our **Cookie Policy**. 

_Navigation Information_ \- You may opt out from the collection of navigation information about your visit to the Site by Google Analytics by using the [Google Analytics Opt-out feature](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

_OBA / Interest Based Advertising -  _The FMD is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) in the U.S., E.U. and Canada and uses third party assurance platforms to comply with the DAA principles. FMD strives to adhere to the self-regulatory organization principles for the DAA (US), the DAAC (Canada) and the EDAA (EU). 

Visitors may opt out of receiving interest-based advertising by advertising networks that may be delivered to them on our platform and other websites. For information about how to opt out of tracking methods for these entities and others, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). These features will opt a Visitor out of many – but not all - of the interest-based advertising activities in which we or third parties engage. 

  * European Union and Switzerland residents should visit the European DAA by [clicking here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).
  * Canadian residents should visit the DAA of Canada by [clicking here](http://youradchoices.ca/choices).
  * S. residents and residents of all other countries or territories not listed above can [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for the DAA site to learn more about the use of cookies, your opt-out choices, and more.

This will opt you out of many – but not all - of the interest-based advertising activities in which we or third parties engage. Choices you make may be browser and device specific. If you delete your cookies or use a different browser or a different computer or device, you may need to update your opt-out choices. Other third-party Sites provide visitors with the ability to opt-out of receiving interest-based ads on their Sites that you need to control through your settings on that Site. For example, to opt out of Google’s use of your online behavior for advertising purposes, visit [Google’s Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/). 

* * *

**EU Residents** \- GDPR provides certain rights for EU residents. You may decline to share certain information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide some of the features and functionality of the Website. These rights include, in accordance with applicable law, the right to object to or request the restriction of processing of your information, and to request access to, rectification, erasure and portability of your own information. Where we process your information on the basis of your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent (noting that such withdrawal does not affect the lawfulness of any Processing performed prior to the date on which we receive notice of such withdrawal, and does not prevent the Processing of your Personal Information in reliance upon any other available legal bases). Requests should be submitted by contacting us (using the contact instructions in Section 14 below). If you are an EU resident and have any unresolved privacy concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily after contacting us, you have the right to contact the appropriate EU Supervisory Authority and lodge a complaint. 

**California Residents** \- In accordance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act, we may collect Personal Information about your online activities when you use the Website. While we give our users many avenues to opt out of providing Personal Information, we do not respond to Web browsers’ “do not track” signals. California’s “Shine the Light” law, Civil Code Section 1798.83, permits our users who are California residents to periodically request and obtain certain information about any Personal Information disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to make such a request or if you wish for us to refrain from gathering your Personal Information, please submit your request using the contact instructions in Section 14 below. 

**Do not Track Policy** \-  Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the website or online service that a user visits, indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked. FMD does not act on “do not track” requests from your browser because, there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret Do Not Track signals and this way, we are able to personalize your experiences on our Websites. 

**Privacy Settings** \- Although we may allow you to adjust your privacy settings to limit access to certain Personal Data, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on the Service. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your information. Further, even after information posted on the Service is removed, caching and archiving services may have saved that information, and other users or third parties may have copied or stored the information available on the Service. We cannot and do not guarantee that information you post on or transmit to the Service will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. 

## 12\. Terms of Use 

For more information concerning your use of our website, please visit our Terms of Use. The FMD Terms of Use is incorporated by reference into this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you review our Terms of Use regularly, in order to review any changes we might make from time to time. 

## 13\. Changes and Updates to Our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and all changes will be effective at the time we post them. If we believe there is a significant change to this Privacy Policy or our data collection and use practices, we will indicate on our websites that our Privacy Policy has changed prior to the change becoming effective. The then-posted version of the Privacy Policy supersedes all prior versions. Your continued access to or use of any of the Services shall be deemed your acceptance of the Privacy Policy.

We urge you to come back to this web page and review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you. 

## 14\. How to Contact Us

Please contact us with any questions, comments or concerns about any of the information in this Policy, your Personal Data, our use and disclosure practices, or your consent choices by email at 

. If you are an EU resident, for matters relating to privacy and data protection, you may contact our **Data Protection Officer** by email at 

.

_Last Update:May 25th 2018_

For more information concerning your rights, please visit our Your Rights

## Please contact us if you have further questions.
